一本漫畫平均有35頁124張圖片
一本漫畫價格1元至14萬
在美國 每天賣出17萬2千本
每年賣出超過6278萬本
收藏家平均擁有3312本
平均一生花一年時間看漫畫
費城百貨公司
1961年
This is Mr Mathison. He's a doctor.
這是馬先生 他是醫生
Are you okay?
你還好吧
An ambulance is on the way.
救護車快到了
Thank you.
謝謝
Is there a name yet?
幫他取名字了
Elijah.
伊萊
Is he supposed to be crying like this?
他這麼哭正常嗎
May l?
我可以抱抱嗎
Can l have him back?
可以還我了嗎
What happened during the delivery?
生產時出了什麼事
Nothing. it was very quick.
沒有 產程很快
The baby just wanted to come right out.
這小子想立刻出世
There were no problems.
一切正常
Did you drop him?
你有摔到他嗎
What?
什麼
Did you drop this baby?
你摔到他了嗎
Jesus Christ, no.
天啊 沒有
inform the ambulance that we have a situation.
通知救護車有特殊狀況
I've never seen... this.
我從未看過...這種情形
it appears that your baby has sustained some fractures
看來你的孩子多處骨折
while inside your uterus.
在你子宮內就骨折了
His arms and his legs are broken.
他的手腳都斷了
主演布魯斯·威利斯
主演塞繆爾·傑克遜
This is East rail 177.
這是東鐵177號列車
Next stop, Philadelphia.
下一站 費城
Are you alone?
這裏有人坐嗎
Yeah.
沒有
好
Someone left this magazine.
這裏有雜誌
Want to take a look at it?
要看嗎
Can l take a look at that one?
我能看那本嗎
Thanks.
謝了
You like sports?
你喜歡運動
it's my field. I represent athletes. I'm an agent.
這是我的職業 我是經紀人
Are you looking for any male synchronized swimmers?
需要男性水上芭蕾舞者嗎
I'm thinking about getting into that.
我正想跳呢
Is that right?
你說真的
I'm afraid of water.
我怕水
Think that's a problem?
那會有問題嗎
You represent someone in Philadelphia?
你去費城出差
I'm meeting this player from Temple University.
我要去天普大學見一個選手
He's a cornerback.
他是個角衛
This kid is 6'1'', 210 pounds.
高6英尺1英吋 重210磅
He runs a 40 in 4.3 seconds.
他跑40碼只需4.3秒
He's gonna be a god.
他絕對會紅
Do you like football?
喜歡美式足球嗎
Not really.
還好吧
I'm David Dunn.
我是鄧大衛
Kelly.
凱莉
Hi, nice to meet you.
幸會
How long are you gonna be in Philadelphia?
你到費城要停留多久
I'm married.
我結婚了
Great.
真好
I'm sorry.
抱歉
What are you Talking about?
你在說什麼
l think you misunderstood.
我想你誤會了
What l was, uh...
我剛才...
saying
是說...
l know. l think I'm going to find another seat.
我想我換個座位好了
l... L didn't mean, uh...
我無意...
That's What he fail to realize.
這就是他沒有意識到的
I look classy, not trashy.
我看起來是優雅 不是垃圾
I look classy, too.
我看起來也很優雅
What about me? Don't l look classy?
那我呢 我不優雅嗎
But I'm afraid you forgot...this!
但是恐怕你忘了這個
Andthis!
還有這個
Where has you been, Banana?
你到哪裏去了 香蕉
Now I've got you, Weasel.
我抓到你了 黃鼠狼
Some cars Are still on fire,
有些車廂仍在燃燒
and the debris is everywhere.
殘骸四散
We are not sure at this time
此時我們無法確定
how rescue personnel Will be able to get on scene at all.
救援人員能到達現場
Second Lf you're just tuning in,
您若是剛轉到這個頻道
East rail train number 177
東鐵177列車
has derailed just outside Philadelphia.
剛剛在費城脫軌
And We're bringing you live coverage from Skycam 4.
請收看來自現場的報導
Yes, that appears to be a rescue ambulance,
是的 有一輛救護車來到
and there are more behind it.
我還看得到後面還有
l can see on the access road.
更多輛都在路上
l don't know how close they're gonna be able to get, David.
不知他們能多接近現場 大衛
These are Woods and, uh, trees.
他們進去了 這裏都是木頭 樹
Uh, it's gonna be a very difficult? rescue effort...
這將是個艱困的救援任務吧 救援資源...
爸坐東鐵177列車
Hi. I'm Dr Dubin.
我是杜醫生
You're in the emergency room in the
這裏是費城市立
Philadelphia City Hospital.
醫院急診室
You were in a serious accident.
你剛遭遇一場嚴重意外
Look at me.
看著我
How are you feeling?
你感覺如何
Okay.
還好
Good.
很好
I'm going to ask you some questions.
我要問你一些問題
Have you ever had any heart
你過去有氣喘
or asthma problems in the past?
或心臟疾病嗎
No.
沒有
Kidney or renal problems?
腎臟或結石的毛病
No.
沒有
Any allergies?
過敏
No.
沒有
Where were you sitting on the train?
你在車上坐哪裏
Against the window.
靠窗
in the passenger car?
在客車車廂
Yeah.
對
Where are the other passengers?
其他旅客呢
Was your family travelling with you?
你有家人同行嗎
No.
沒有
Did you get up from your seat?
你有離開座位嗎
Are you certain you were in the passenger car?
你確定你當時在客車車廂
Yes.
是的
Why are you looking at me like that?
你幹什麼那樣看著我
Your train derailed. Some kind of malfunction.
你坐的火車出軌 機械故障
They only found 2 people alive so far.
目前只有兩人生還
You and this man.
你和這個人
His skull Was cracked open
他腦殼破裂
and most of his left side Was crushed.
左半身被壓扁
And to answer your question, there are2 reasons
我這麼回答你吧
Why l'm looking at you like this.
我這樣看你有兩個理由
One, because it seems in a few minutes
一 似乎再過幾分鐘
that you Will officially be the only
你將成為這事故的
survivor of this train Wreck.
唯一生還者
And two...
二...
because you didn't break one bone.
你全身毫髮無損
You don't have a scratch on you.
連擦傷都沒有
David?
大衛
What happened... in New York?
紐約那邊怎樣了
l don't think l got the job.
我沒得到那個工作
I'm still going, uh...
我還是會去...
I'm still moving there.
我還是會搬去那裏
just...
只是...
Oh, just not now.
只是不是現在
Good night.
晚安
東鐵事故家屬告別式
Sara Elaston...
尹莎拉
social worker at Broad and Locust Community Centre.
博魯社區中心的社工
We pray for your soul.
我們為你的靈魂祈禱
Kevin Elliot, businessman, father of 6.
艾凱文 商人 六個孩子的父親
We pray for your soul.
我們為你的靈魂祈禱
Glen Stevens...
史葛蘭
researcher in the area of leukemia...
白血癥的研究學者
at Drexel University.
任教於德瑟大學
We pray for your soul.
我們為你的靈魂祈禱
jennifer Pennyman...
潘珍妮
third grade teacher At Jefferson Elementary.
傑佛遜小學三年級老師
Wepray for your soul.
我們為你的靈魂祈禱
限量珍藏
你這輩子生過幾天病
Yes?
什麼事
Is Noel in, ma'am?
老諾來了嗎
No, sir, he is not.
沒有
l read about you in the paper.
我在報上看到你的新聞
l was in an accident once, too.
我也出過意外
A horse almost trampled me to death.
我差點被一匹馬踩死
Had him put down.
它安樂死了
That's a sad story.
真糟糕
Could you ask Noel something for me, please?
請你幫我問老諾一件事
Proceed.
說吧
Would you ask him to check how many sick days
請他查一下我到現在為止
I've taken since I've worked here?
請過幾天病假
That the entire message?
就這樣
Yes, ma'am.
是的
Thank you.
謝謝你
Hey, Noel.
老諾
What, you hit your head on that train?
你腦袋被火車撞到了
Get your brain to start Working again?
腦袋又開始能運轉了
What?
什麼
40.
40塊
40 what?
什麼40塊
You're getting a 40 a week raise.
你每周加薪40塊
That's it.
就這樣
l checked. You were right.
我查過了
You've never taken a sick day.
你沒請過病假
5 years, no sick day. l get it. You want a raise.
五年全勤 我懂的 你要加薪
Smart way to make your point.
這方法很聰明
Is Joseph okay?
喬瑟還好吧
Yeah. He's asleep.
他睡了
l wanted to ask you a question.
我要問你一個問題
it's gonna sound a little strange,
聽起來會有點奇怪
but, uh, just think about it for a second, okay?
但我要你想一想 好嗎
Okay.
好
When's the last time l was sick?
我上回生病是何時
Do you remember?
你記得嗎
Um, l don't know.
我不知道
it's been a while.
有一陣子了吧
l haven't been sick this year, l know that.
我今年還沒生過病 我知道
Okay.
是的
Do you remember me getting sick?
你記得我生過病嗎
not a specific day.
不太清楚
What's this about?
問這幹嘛
Audrey, do you remember me ever getting sick?
奧莉 你記得我生過病嗎
In the 3 years we lived in this house?
在我們住這裏的三年時光內
In the old apartment?
住老公寓的時候
Before Joseph was born? Before we ever got married?
喬瑟出生前 我們結婚前
l can't remember.
我記不得了
Don't you think that's kind of weird,
你不認為這有點奇怪嗎
not remembering one cold or a fever or a sore throat?
不記得有發燒或感冒過
What do you think it means?
你想這代表什麼意思
l think it means probably too tired to remember.
我想也許是太累才想不起來
費城西區
1974年
No more sitting in this room.
不准再呆坐房內
l let it go on long enough.
我受夠了
I'm not going out there any more.
我不出去
I'm not getting hurt again.
我不要再受傷了
This was the last time, l told you.
我說過了 這是最後一次
You can't do anything about that.
你就不能做些什麼嗎
You might fall between this chair and that television.
你隨時隨地都可能跌倒
lf that's what God has planned for you,
上帝旨意如此
that's what's gonna happen.
無法違背
You can't hide from it sitting in a room.
躲在房裏是沒用的
They call me Mr Glass at school
同學們叫我玻璃娃娃
because l break like glass.
因我跟玻璃一樣易碎
You make this decision now...
你現在自己做決定吧...
to be afraid...
這樣你心裏滿懷恐懼
and you will never turn back.
而且你也將永遠活在恐懼中
Your whole life, you will always be afraid.
你這輩子都無法停止恐懼
l got a present for you.
我有個禮物要送你
Why?
為什麼
Forget why.
別管為什麼
You want it or not?
你想不想要
Well, go get it, then.
那就去拿吧
Where is it?
它在哪裏
On a bench...
在對街的...
across the street.
長椅上
Someone's going to take it.
會被別人拿走的
Then you better get out there soon.
所以你最好快去拿
動感漫畫
l bought a whole bunch.
我買了一整套
There'll be one of these waiting for you
每次只要你出來這裏
every time you want to come out here.
就有一本在等你
They say this one has a surprise ending.
聽說這本結局很特別
This is from Fritz Campion's own library.
這是富利的私人珍藏
This is before the first
在他68年推出第一本
issue of the comic book hit the stands in 1968.
漫畫前所畫的作品
it's a classic depiction of good vs. evil.
善與惡的典型描繪方式
Notice the square jaw of Slayer,
注意史雷典型的
common in most comic heroes.
英雄方形下巴
And the slightly disproportionate size
還有賈卦不成比例的
of Jaguaro's head to his body.
頭與身體
This again is common, but only in villains.
只有壞蛋是這樣畫的
The thing to notice about this piece,
這幅畫值得注意的是
the thing that makes it very, very special
讓它之所以與眾不同的地方
is its realistic depiction of its figures.
就是寫實的人物描繪
When the characters Reached the magazine,
那些人物登上
they Were exaggerated...
雜誌時被誇大了
a sal Ways happens.
事情一向如此
This is vintage.
這是幅傑作
Well... wrap it up.
好 包起來 我買了
You've made a considerably wise decision.
你的決定是睿智的
Well, my kid's gonna go berserk.
我的小孩會高興死的
Once again, please?
什麼
My son Jeb it's a gift for him.
我兒子傑伯 這是送給他的
How old is Jeb?
傑伯幾歲了
He's 4.
四歲
No.
不
No, no, no, no, no.
不...
You need to go. Now.
請你走吧
What'd l say?
我說錯什麼了
Do you see any Teletubbies in here?
我這裏有天線寶寶嗎
Do you see a slender plastic tag
你有看到我衣服上
clipped to my shirt with my name printed on it?
別了寫有我名字的塑料標籤嗎
Did you see a little Asian child
你有看到我這裏
with a blank expression sitting outside
有投幣就會唱歌
in a mechanical helicopter
還能載個亞洲小孩
that shakes when you put quarters in it?
轉動的直升機嗎
No?
沒有吧
Well, that's what you see at a toy store,
那是玩具店才有的東西
and you must think you're in a toy store,
你一定以為你進了玩具店
because you're here shopping for an infant named Jeb.
因為你要買東西送你的小鬼傑伯
Now, one of us has made a gross error
我們之中有人弄錯
and wasted the other person's valuable time.
浪費了彼此寶貴的時間
This is an art gallery, my friend,
這裏是藝廊
and this... is a piece of art.
而這是...一件藝術品
限量珍藏
We're by appointment only.
我們只接待預約顧客
l got a card from this store.
我收到貴店的卡片
Congratulations, you have a mailbox.
恭喜 你有一個信箱
The exhibition isn't for 2 weeks.
展覽已經過了兩周了
This one was under the windshield wiper of my car.
這張是夾在我車子擋風玻璃上的
How certain are you that you've never taken ill?
你有多少把握自己沒生過病
75%
百分之七十五
Well... that's not certain at all, is it?
那還不算很有把握吧
That's hole number one.
那是第一個問題
l'm going to be extremely skeptical about all this.
我要嚴格檢驗我的理論
About all What?
什麼理論
I'm assuming you've never been injured.
我假定你沒受過傷
Would l be wrong in that assumption?
我沒說錯吧
Dad's been injured.
我爸爸受過傷
Is the child correct?
這孩子說得對嗎
Yes, sir.
是的
in college, l was in a car accident.
我念大學時出過車禍
Was It serious?
嚴重嗎
He couldn't play football any more.
他後來就不能打足球了
That's hole number2.
那是第二個問號
That's a big one.
很大的問號
Mr Price, can we talk about the note
談談你留在
that you left on my car?
我車上的卡片吧
I've studied the form of comics intimately.
我仔細的研究過漫畫
I've spent a third of my life in a hospital bed
我三分之一的人生都在住院
with nothing else to do but read.
住院時只能看書
l believe comics are our last link
我相信漫畫與古代
to an ancient way of passing on history.
傳承歷史的方法有所連結
The Egyptians drew on the walls.
埃及人在壁上作畫
Countries all over the world
全世界的國家仍以
still pass on knowledge through pictorial forms.
繪畫的形式傳承知識
l believe comics are a form of history
漫畫是歷史的一種形式
that someone somewhere felt or experienced.
描繪某人的感覺或經驗
Then, of course, those experiences and that history
然後 理所當然的
got chewed up in the commercial machine,
那經驗和歷史被商業機器吞噬
got jazzed up, made titillating,
過度包裝 刺激感官
cartooned for the sale rack.
被拍成卡通四處銷售
This city has seen its share Of disasters.
這城市發生過許多悲劇
l watched the aftermath of that plane crash.
我看過飛機墜毀
l watched the carnage of the hotel fire.
旅館大火
l watched the news waiting to hear
我看著新聞
a very specific combination of words,
等待一連串特別的字句
but they never came.
但我從未聽見過
Then one day l saw a news story about a train accident,
有天我看到火車意外的報導
and l heard them.
我終於聽見了
There is a sole survivor,
事故中只有一位生還者
and he is miraculously unharmed.
他奇跡似地毫髮無傷
l have something called osteogenesis imperfecta.
我患了延遲性骨發生不全
lt's a genetic disorder.
這是遺傳病
l don't make a particular protein very Well,
我無法製造某種蛋白質
and it makes my bones very low in density.
所以我的骨質疏鬆
Very easy to break.
很容易骨折
I've had 54 breaks in my life,
我骨折過54次
and l have the tamest version of this disorder,
我的情況是最輕微的
type one.
第一型
There are type2, type3, type 4.
還有第二 第三 第四型
Type 4 don't last very long.
第四型都活不久
So that's how it popped into my head.
所以我才會有這個想法
lf there is someone like me in the world,
若世上有人跟我一樣
and I'm at one end of the spectrum,
我在極端值的一端
couldn't there be someone else
會不會有人
the opposite of me at the other end?
是在另一端
Someone who doesn't get sick,
一個不生病
who doesn't get hurt like the rest of us?
不會受傷的人
And he probably doesn't even know it.
而他也許根本不自知
The kind of person these stories are about.
這些故事裏所描繪的那種人
A person put here to protect the rest of us.
一個能夠保護我們的人
To guard us.
護衛我們的人
You think my dad's a real
你想我爸是...
l don't think anything right now.
我什麼都沒想
lt's apossibility
有這個可能性
one With many holes.
有許多問號
joseph, don't take another sip of that water.
喬瑟 別再喝那杯水
Go throw it in the trash.
把它扔掉
But, Dad
但是
Do it now, please.
快去
l see guys like you All the time in my Work.
我工作時看過太多你這種人了
You find someone you want to take advantage of,
你們想佔人便宜
you tell them a fantastic story,
就告訴人們一個奇特的故事
and somewhere in there you say it
而你們心裏想的是
l just need your credit card number
我只要你的信用卡號碼
a small down payment
一小筆頭款
This morning was the first morning
今天是我第一次
that l could remember
早晨起床時
that l didn't open my eyes and feel
不會感覺到
sadness.
悲傷
l thought the person that wrote that note
我以為留言的人
had an answer for me.
會給我答案
l'm gonna leave now.
我要走了
Good luck with your exhibition.
祝展覽順利
So, what kind of job do you have, David?
你是做什麼的 大衛
You said you've met guys like me in your work.
你說你看過很多像我一樣的人
What exactly is it that you do?
你到底是做什麼的
l work at the University Stadium.
我在大學體育場工作
I'm a security guard.
我是警衛
車事故唯一生還者是本地人
戰士隊邁向冠軍
本地足球明星在重大車禍中受傷
火車事故唯一生還者是本地人
I've come to a decision.
我做了一個決定
Okey
你說
l just want to ask you something, okay?
我想問你一件事
And you can be totally honest.
你要誠實回答
I'm prepared for any answer,
我已準備面對任何答案
and it won't affect me.
不受影響
Have you been with anyone?
你有跟別人交往過嗎
l mean, since we've been having problems.
就打我們出問題之後
The answer won't affect me.
你的答案不會影響我的
l just need to know, you know?
我只是需要知道
it won't affect me either way.
不管怎樣都影響不了我
No.
沒有
Sorry, David. Sorry.
抱歉 大衛
Anyway...
總之...
my decision is...
我的決定是...
that l want to start again.
我想再來一次
That l want it to be like it was in the beginning.
我想一切再從頭開始
And it's a big deal that you walked away from that train.
你的生還意義重大
l feel like it's a second chance.
我覺得那是第二次的機會
And if you feel like asking me out sometime,
你若想約我出去什麼的
it'd be okay.
沒問題
Go for Dunn.
我是小鄧
It's Jenkins.
我是傑金
Look, We got a guy over at gate 17C With a bogus ticket.
17C入口有人持假票
Say she knows you. He Won't tell me his name.
他說認識你 不肯透露姓名
What's he look like?
他長什麼樣子
Why is it, do you think,
為什麼這世界上
that of all the professions in the world,
這麼多職業 你為什麼
you chose protection?
要選擇安保
You are a very strange man.
你真的很怪
You could have been a tax accountant.
你可以當一個會計師
You could have owned your own gym.
你可以擁有自己的健身房
You could've opened a chain of restaurants.
你可以開一個連鎖餐廳
You could've done one of 1 0,000 things,
你本可以做了成千上萬件有意義的事
but in the end, you chose to protect people.
但最後 你選擇了保護人們
You made that decision,
你做了那個決定
and l find that very, very interesting.
而我覺得相當有趣
Now all l need is your credit card number.
現在我要你的信用卡號碼
That last part was a joke.
最後一句是開玩笑
You're a big sports fan, are you?
你是運動迷嗎
it's starting to intrigue me.
我開始對運動有興趣了
it gets heaviest 10 minutes before kick off.
開場前十分鐘最擠
just give me a minute.
等我一分鐘
ls there a problem?
有問題嗎
The tall guy in the camouflage jacket.
那個穿迷彩夾克的高個子
Sometimes people carry weapons in here,
有時人們喝多了
and they drink too much.
帶了武器過來
lf the team's not doing good,
要是球隊表現不好
bad things can happen.
就會出事
We do pat downs Of the crowd
我們搜身好嚇跑
to discourage people from carrying.
那些攜械的人
lf he's carrying, he'll step out of line.
要是他有攜械 他會走出隊伍
l got you a seat up in the yellow section.
我安排你坐黃區
it's in the nosebleeds,
那區地勢最高
but at least you won't get spit on.
沒人會吐你口水
All right.
好了
How'd you know that guy you bumped
你怎會知道
was carrying a weapon?
那傢伙攜械
l don't know.
我不知道
Maybe it was that camouflage army jacket he was wearing.
也許是因為他穿著野戰外套吧
Those guys like to carry hunting knives and stuff for show.
那種人都喜歡帶刀帶槍的
You thought he was carrying a knife?
你認為他身上有刀子
l thought he was carrying something, yeah.
我認為他帶了傢伙
But not a knife.
但不是一把刀
l got a...
我看到...
picture ofa silver gun with a black grip
一幅畫面
tucked in his pants.
他腰上有把黑柄的銀色手槍
You know, like on TV.
就跟電視上演的一樣
You have good instincts for things like that?
你對那種事直覺很準嗎
Like what?
什麼事
Knowing when people have done something wrong.
知道人們做了不對的事
Yeah.
對
Have you ever tried to develop it?
有試過開發這能力嗎
l don't know what you're asking me.
我不懂你在說什麼
Your skill.
你的技巧
Look, l got to be down on the sidelines during the game.
比賽時我要在場邊
You can get to your seat right down here
你可以到你的座位去了
Characters in comics are often attributed special powers
漫畫人物通常都有特異功能
invisibility, X Ray vision, things of that sort.
隱形 透視之類的能力
Okay.
好了
l don't want to play this game any more.
我不想再談這個了
it's an exaggeration ofthe truth.
那是現實的誇張表現
Maybe it's based on something
也許那就像是種
as simple as instinct.
直覺
But he might not have been carrying anything.
他也許什麼也沒帶
But he might have been carrying a silver gun
但是他的腰間也許
with a black grip tucked in his pants.
真有把黑柄銀手槍
Dunn.
小鄧
l gotta go.
我得走了
Yeah, l know. I'll be right down.
知道了 我馬上下來
One last question.
最後一個問題
What?
說吧
That car accident you were in.
你上次出的車禍
Was there anyone else involved?
當時還有別人嗎
Yeah.
有
My wife Audrey.
我太太
She was in the car with me.
她跟我一起
Have a good life, Elijah.
祝你愉快
Next time, try to buy your tickets
下次別跟著
at an authorized sales location.
買黃牛票了
I'm on my way.
我馬上到
...into the investigation of train 177
177列車事故調查
being conducted at the East rail holding Warehouses.
在東鐵庫房展開
The city council Has stepped up plans to pass a bill...
市議會計劃通過一項法案
requiring higher standards for inspection and maintenance
要求對大費城地區的鐵路
of all rail transportation in Philadelphia
運輸執行更高的
and its outlying districts.
檢驗及維修標準
Hold up a second!
等一等
l just Want to ask you something.
我只想問你一個問題
Dad!
爸
Hey, Dad!
Dad!
爸
joseph, do you know how mad your mother would be
約瑟夫 你媽要是知道
if she knew you were playing football?
你玩足球就完了
Are you gonna tell?
你不會說吧
You want to play last of the downs?
來打最後一輪進攻吧
We got a big guy like you.
我們隊上有好手
You could play on opposite sides.
你可以加入對方
He's Potter's cousin.
他是考波特
He's starting cornerback at Temple University.
天普大學的先發角衛
He's going pro in the draft.
他要參加選秀會
They say he can run the 40 in 4.3 seconds.
聽說他40碼只跑4.3秒
I've heard.
我聽說過了
You can beat him, Dad.
你可以打敗他的
Let's beat'em.
去痛宰他們吧
I'm gonna go in.
我要進屋去
just play one set of downs. l told them you were great.
就打一輪 我說過你很行的
Why'd you do that?
你為何那樣說
just one.
一輪就好
I'm gonna go in. I've got some things to do.
我要進屋 我有事
What things?
什麼事
I'm gonna work out.
我要健身
I'll help you.
我幫你
l don't need
不需要
l can't play, guys!
我不能玩了
I'm working out with my dad!
我要幫我爸健身
How much did you put on there?
你加多重
You put too much. That's 250 pounds.
太重了 250磅
How much can you lift?
你能舉多重
That's the most l ever lifted.
這是我舉過最重的
That could've been dangerous, Joseph.
這很危險的
Why don't you go upstairs now
你上樓去吧
and let me finish up, okay?
我自己練
I'll take it off. I'll help you right.
我拿掉重量 好好幫你
You think you could have beaten up Bruce Lee?
你想你能打敗李小龍嗎
No.
不能
l mean, if you knew karate.
我是說 若你會空手道的話
No.
不能
What if he wasn't allowed to kick,
要是他不能踢
and you were really mad at him?
你又氣瘋了
No, Joseph.
不能
How much did you take off?
你拿掉多少重量
l lied.
我騙你的
You added?
你加重量
How much is it?
總共多重
270 pounds.
270磅
Let's put more.
再加點重量
Okay.
好
Why don't you move back a little
你退後點
just to be safe, okay?
安全第一
More?
再加
You should never do anything like this.
你不可以學我
You know that, right?
知道嗎
What do you do If something bad happens?
要是出事你要怎麼辦
Get Mom.
去找媽
Right.
沒錯
How much did you put on that time?
這回你加了多少
All of it.
全部
What else can we use?
還能加什麼
How much is it?
多重
How much is it, Dad?
總共多重
About 350 pounds.
350磅左右
Fracture of the fifth Metacarpal of the right hand,
右手掌骨折
as well as multiple fractures
第6 7 8根肋骨
of the sixth, seventh, and eighth ribs.
也多數骨折
The worst of the injury, however,
傷的最嚴重的
was sustained to the right leg
是右腳
in the form of a spiral fracture.
螺旋骨折
There were 1 4 breaks.
斷了14處
it simply shattered.
完全粉碎
They call me Mr Glass.
他們叫我玻璃娃娃
Who does?
誰
Kids.
孩子們
Are you All right, Mr Price?
你還好吧
Shall l continue?
要繼續嗎
Pins Were placed through out the length of the leg.
整只腿已打上鋼釘
The use of a Wheelchair
你要以輪椅
Will be needed For a 2 monthperiod.
代步二個月
The use of crutches Will Follow for 12 to 14months.
接下來12至14個月用枴杖
Hospital stay Will range from 5 to 8days
住院治療5至8天
folloWed by 9 to 12 months of physical therapy.
其後9至12個月做物理治療
Prescribed medication for pain management
我給你疼痛
Will take the usual forms of morphine drip,
控制用一般的
perco cet, darvocet.
嗎啡止痛
Your 1 0:00 is here.
你十點的病人來了
The hospital discharged him this morning.
他今早出院
Thanks.
謝謝
Elijah, right?
伊萊 對吧
We're gonna prevent any substantial atrophy
我們用這來防止你
of your good leg with this,
腿部萎縮
and it works your quadriceps.
這也能鍛煉你的四頭肌
How long have you been married?
你結婚多久了
12 years.
12年
How'd you get together?
你們為何會結婚
I'm a little nervous being here.
我有點緊張
l ask too many questions when I'm nervous.
我緊張時就愛拚命提問題
A car accident.
一場車禍
Now you're going to have to tell me more.
你告訴我更多細節了
My husband was a star athlete in college,
他原是大學足球明星
and we were in an accident together.
我們發生一場車禍
Our car flipped on an icy road,
翻車了
and we were both injured,
我們受傷
and he couldn't play football any more.
他無法再打球了
And if that hadn't happened,
要不是那樣
we probably wouldn't have been together.
我們也不會結婚
How so?
傷到哪裏
l think we should talk about your rehab.
我們該談你的復健治療
You don't have to answer if you don't want to.
不想答就不用答
So, tell me more about the quad machine.
跟我說說那台機器吧
lt prevents atrophy by...
它可以預防肌肉萎縮
l couldn't spend my life with someone who played football.
我不能跟足球選手共度一生
it's pretty much that simple.
就這麼簡單
And l don't hate the game.
我不討厭球賽
l admire the amount of skill it involves.
我欣賞包括其中的技能
And like everyone else,
跟別人一樣
l was in awe of the way he played it,
我一樣覺得他很棒
but football, in many ways, is the opposite of what l do.
但足球跟我的職業背道而馳
You're rewarded the more you punish your opponent.
痛宰對手卻能得到獎賞
You know, it's too much about violence,
太暴力了
and l don't want violence in my life.
我不喜歡暴力
it's not a thing many people can understand, but...
很多人都不能瞭解這點
Anyway,
總之...
fate stepped in with that car accident
命運讓我跳過了
and took football out other equation.
這個足球給我帶來的障礙
And everyone lived Happily ever after.
而且所有人都皆大歡喜
Sort of.
算吧
What part of David's body Was in jured?
大衛傷到哪裏
Who said my husband's name was David?
我沒提過我丈夫叫大衛
A 737 crashes on takeoff
一架737客機起飛時失事
172 die, no survivors.
死了172人 無人生還
A hotel fire downtown, 211 die,
一棟旅館火災 211人死亡
no survivors.
無人生還
An East rail train derails, 7.5 miles outside the city
一列火車在郊外出軌
131 die, one survivor.
131人死亡 1人生還
He is unharmed.
他毫髮無損
I've spoken with your husband about his survival.
我跟你丈夫談過他的倖存
l suggested a rather unbelievable possibility.
我告訴他一個可能性
Since then,
從那時起
I've come to believe that possibility,
我就相信那個可能性
however unbelievable, is now more aprobability.
現在它可更有可能了
And what was it you suggested?
你告訴他什麼
These are mediocre times, Mrs Dunn.
這是個平凡的時代 鄧太太
People a restarting to lose hope.
人們失去希望
it's hard for many to believe
許多人不信...
there are extraordinary things inside themselves
他們自己有不凡之處
as Well as others.
跟其他人一樣
l hope you can keep an open mind.
希望你能敞開心胸
Excuse me, sir?
抱歉
Can you step out of line, please?
請你出來一下
We've been having some problems
我們有些問題
with people selling drugs here in the stadium.
關於體育場裏毒品交易
Would you mind if l check your pockets?
不介意我檢查你的口袋吧
Raise your arms, please.
請把手舉起來
Come on, raise them up.
快 舉起來
l just got here, man.
我才剛到這裏
Can l put my hands down now?
能把手放下了嗎
Can l go?
可以走了吧
Yeah.
可以
Hope you find them.
真希望你找到什麼
Yo, Dunn.
小鄧
Yeah.
請說
l just came into the office.
我剛到辦公室
Your kid Was hurt.
你小孩受傷了
Where is he?
他在哪裏
Some play Rehearsal at school.
在學校
He Wants you to come down there.
他要你立刻過去
Is that your dad?
那是你爸
l bet my dad could beat up your dad.
我敢賭我爸一定能打贏你爸
No. He, uh... he insisted we call only you,
不 他堅持我們只通知你
though we had some trouble tracking you down.
雖然你很難找
l mean, you're not on our list.
資料上沒寫你
Audrey handles this type of stuff.
這類的事都由奧莉處理
Oh. What type of stuff?
哪類的事
joseph stuff.
喬瑟的事
Do l need to put any smelly ointment on him or anything?
我需要幫他敷藥嗎
No, no. it's more emotional damage
不用 他心靈上的創傷較重
not, not too serious, physically.
身體上的傷不重
Nothing like when l sent you to the hospital.
不像以前我送你就醫一樣
When was that?
什麼
My office was on the other side of the building back then.
我的辦公室以前在另一邊
You don't remember me, do you?
你不記得我了
No, ma'am.
不記得
l had red hair.
我以前一頭紅髮
Well, you Were a little younger than Joseph When it happened.
事故發生當時你比喬瑟還小
Did you know that we changed
知道嗎...
the rules of conduct around the pool because of you?
我們因你改變泳池活動規則
The kids Still tell about it
孩子們現在還在議論
like it Was some sort of ghost story.
把它當成像鬼故事一樣
Did you know there Was a kid nearly drowned in that pool?
你知道泳池裏差點淹死人嗎
He lay on the bottom Of the pool for 5 minutes,
他沉在池底五分鐘
and When they pulled him out,
他被撈出來時
he Was dead.
他已經死了
We let them tell it.
我們隨他們講
lt help skeep them safe.
注意安全就好
You still phobic Of Water?
你還怕水嗎
it Was Potter And another guy.
是波特和另一個人
They Were messing With this Chinese girl in the dressing room.
他們在更衣室捉弄一個女生
You can't let Bad things happen to good people, right?
你不喜歡好人遇上壞事 對吧
That's your code, right? That's the hero's code.
那是你的天性 英雄的天性
l tried to make them stop,
我想叫他們住手
but they kept pushing me down,
但他們把我推下
and they wouldn't let me get back up.
不讓我起來
l thought maybe because you're my dad...
我想也許因為你是我爸
l thought l might be like you.
我可能也會像你
I'm not like you.
我不像你
You are like me.
你像我
We can both get hurt.
我們都會受傷
l'm just an ordinary man.
我只是普通人
No, you're not.
你不是
Why do you keep saying that?
你為什麼一直那麼說
Eliijah Price came to visit me at the centre today.
普伊萊今天到復健中心找我
jesus.
天啊
He didn't do anything. He just...
他沒做什麼 只是...
told me his theory.
跟我說他的理論
That's sad, when patients get like that.
病人變成這樣真是悲哀
They lose reality.
神智不清
Joseph, what the hell are you doing?
喬瑟 你這是幹嘛
Oh, my God.
天啊
You don't believe. I'll show you. You can't get hurt.
你不相信 你不會受傷的
That gun's not loaded. He doesn't know where l keep the bullets.
那沒上膛 他不知道子彈放哪
ln your Rookie of the Year trophy.
在你的新人獎獎盃里
Joseph, did you load that gun?
喬瑟 你上膛了
You won't get hurt.
你不會受傷的
Eliijah Was Wrong.
伊萊錯了
When did he meet Eliijah?
他怎麼會見過伊萊
He was with me when l met him.
跟我一起去見的
No one believes him.
沒人相信他
joseph, listen to me.
喬瑟 聽我說
Sometimes when people get sick or hurt
有時人們生病或受傷太久
for a long time, like Elijah,
就像伊萊...
their mind gets hurt, too,
他們心靈也病了
and they start to think things, that aren't true.
會妄想
He told me what he thought about your father.
他跟我談你爸
it isn't true.
那不是真的
I'll show you.
我讓你見識見識
Do you remember the story about,
記得那個差點
about the boy that almost drowned in the pool?
淹死的小孩吧
That was me they were talking about.
他們說的是我
l almost died. That was me.
我差點淹死
- You're lying. - I'm not lying, okay?
- 你說謊 - 我沒有
l just didn't remember it, that's all.
我只是忘了
Joseph, you know your father was injured in college.
你爸大學時受過傷
You know that. You know all about that.
你知道的 你很清楚
Don't do it. He'll die, Joseph.
別開槍 他會死的
I'll just shoot him once.
我只射他一槍
joseph, listen to what your mot
喬瑟 聽你媽...
Don't be scared.
不要怕
if you pull that trigger, I'm going to leave.
你要是扣板機 我就搬走
Do you understand? l'm going to go to New York.
懂嗎 我要去紐約
You're right.
沒錯
Lf you pull that trigger, that bullet is just going to bounce off me,
如果你開槍 子彈還是會從我身上彈開
and I'm not going to be hurt,
我不會受傷
but then I'm going to go upstairs
但我接著會上樓去拿行李
and I'm going to pack and I'm going to leave for New York.
動身前往紐約
Why?
為什麼
Because l thought We Were just starting
因為我以為我們是
to be friends for real,
好朋友
and friends will listen to each other.
朋友會聽彼此的話
And they don't shoot each other, do they, Audrey?
他們不互相傷害 對吧
No shooting friends, joseph.
不能傷害朋友 喬瑟
Joseph...
喬瑟
you are about to be in big trouble!
你的麻煩大了
Now, l am your father, and l am telling you
我是你父親
to put that goddamn gun down right now!
我叫你立刻把槍放下
One...
一
Two...
二
l followed the guy in the camouflage jacket.
我追上穿野戰外套的那個傢伙
He had a silver gun with a black grip
他腰間真有一把
tucked in the back of his pants.
黑柄銀色手槍
Were you really injured in that car accident in college?
你大學車禍時真的有受傷
Because l believe you faked it.
我覺得你是裝的
l believe you took the opportunity
我認為你藉機結束
to end your football career, no questions asked.
你的足球生涯
And l think you did it, of all things, for a woman.
而且我覺得這一切你都是為了一個女人
l guess that makes sense.
那很合理
Heh. Football's, what, Just 1 0 years,
足球能打多久 十年
but love...
但愛...
Hmm. Now, that's forever.
則是永恆
And that little bit of sadness in the mornings you spoke of?
你說過早晨起床時的悲傷感
l think l know what that is. Perhaps you're not doing
我想我知道那是什麼了 你並沒有
what you're supposed to be doing.
在做你應該做的事情
Most guns have a black or silver handle.
大多數槍有一個黑色或銀色的把手
l had a 50 50 shot of getting the colour right.
我有一個50式手槍正好符合
That's not What l Witnessed.
那不是我親眼目睹
Stop.
夠了
Stop messing with my life, Elijah.
別再來擾亂我的生活 伊萊賈
My son almost shot me last night,
我兒子因你的話
because he wanted to prove you were right.
差點對我開槍
l never said you couldn't be killed.
我沒說你有不死之身
l never said that.
我從沒說過
My wife was right.
我的妻子是對的
There have been 3 major disasters,
三場大災難
and you Were the only one unharmed.
你是唯一毫髮無傷的
l have been sick.
我生過病
When l was a kid, l spent a week in the hospital
在我小的時候 我因為肺炎
getting better from pneumonia.
而住了院
l almost drowned.
我差點溺死
2 skinny little kids
兩個小孩惡作劇
were fooling around in a pool dunking me,
把我扔進水塘裏
and l swallowed some water.
我喝很多水
They didn't know it, and it almost killed me.
他們不知道 我差點因此身亡
Heroes don't get killed like that.
英雄不會死的如此慘
Normal people do, right?
普通人會 對嗎
l don't need to see you any more, okay?
我不想再看到你了
Please stay away from my family.
請離我的家人遠一點
Hey, man, it's 20 after. it's time to choose.
老兄 已經打烊20分鐘了 可以選你要的了
l gotta head.
我要走了
You better not be Jacking off
你可別邊看小本漫畫
to the Japanese comics, l swear to God.
邊打手槍
Look, man, l didn't know you were in a...
我不知道你坐輪椅
just choose something, all right?
總之快點選吧
The baby sitter's here.
保姆到了
Should we cancel?
要取消嗎
I'm fine.
我很好
We can do this another time.
我們可以改天再去
Don't lie.
別說謊了
I'm fine. l just got mixed up.
我很好 我只是有點困惑
How about we just go for a couple drinks?
我們去喝點東西吧
Okay, look, man, I'm just going to wheel you out.
聽著 我要推你出去
All right? You can think about things outside on the sidewalk.
你可以在路邊想清楚
l got to get some chicken in me, you know what I'm saying?
我要去吃點東西
Shit!
媽的
Man, l don't care if you are in a wheelchair.
老兄 我不管你在輪椅上還是怎麼樣
lf you do that again, I'm calling 50.
再這樣我就叫警察了
That's it, crackerjack.
夠了 怪人
You're going to be sitting your ass in jail now.
你等著坐牢吧
守衛者
How much for this one?
這本多少錢
Rust?
鐵銹色
Yeah.
對
As a colour, not as rust.
但那顏色不叫鐵銹色
You know, like... rust coloured paint or wood.
那是叫紅褐色
l didn't know that.
我真的不知道
mine's still brown.
我還是最愛棕色
Okay, my turn.
換我了
Favourite song?
最喜歡的歌曲
Soft and Wet by the Artist Formerly Known as Prince.
王子唱的 "柔潤"
what?
什麼
We're supposed to be honest.
我們應該要坦誠的
Soft and Wet.
"柔潤"
That's very interesting.
真有意思
Okay, my turn.
好 換我了
When was the first time... the thought
你何時開始想...
popped into your head we might not make it?
我們可能無法廝守終身
That's not the game.
遊戲不包括這個
it's the first date. There aren't any rules.
這是約會 沒有規則
Don't know for sure.
我不確定
Think carefully.
仔細想
What about the game?
遊戲呢
it's over. l won.
結束了 我贏了
Look, maybe it wasn't a specific moment.
也許不是什麼特定時間
Maybe it was a time
也許只是...
l had a nightmare one night,
有天晚上我做了個惡夢
and... l didn't wake you up, so you could tell me that it was okay.
而我沒叫醒你 要你安慰我
l think that was the first time.
我想就是打那時候開始的
Does that count?
那算嗎
That counts.
算
Do you knowingly keep me and Joseph at a distance?
你是故意疏離我和喬瑟
Yes.
對
Why?
為什麼
l don't know.
我不知道
l just don't feel right, Audrey.
我就是覺得不對勁
Something's...
有事情...
Just not right.
不大對勁
Do you resent us, David?
你討厭我們嗎
Resent the life you have?
你討厭你的生活
l mean, there were a lot of other things you could've done after college.
大學畢業後你本可以做許多事
These were your choices.
這些是你選擇的
You know, even if it meant we couldn't have been together,
就算會讓我們無法廝守
l never would've wished that injury on you.
我也不願你受傷
What you could do physically was a gift.
你的體能是上天的恩賜
l never would've wished it to go away.
我從未希望你失去它
You know that, right?
你知道的 對吧
You had 2 calls afterJoseph went to bed
喬瑟上床後有兩通電話找你
One came through while l was on the other line,
第一通是我正在通話時插播的
There Was an emergency With my sister.
我姐自助燙髮出了點麻煩
Who called through?
誰打來的
someone from New York,
一個人從紐約打來
uh, about a security job. They Want to hire you.
說什麼保全工作 你被錄取了
l didn't know you guys were moving to New York.
我怎麼不知道你們要搬去紐約
We weren't all going to move.
不是全家去
l let the answering machine pick up the other call.
另一通是答錄機接的
Great.
糟糕
Look, let's just be honest here. We're just at the beginning,
開誠佈公吧 我們才剛開始
and l don't expect you or l to change
我並不期望你改變...
the course of where our lives were headed
原來的計劃
because of one date.
就因為一次約會
And if you do go to New York, we can develop this.
你去了紐約 我們還是有機會
We'll just be forced to take it slow.
只是步調會慢一點
And in the end, l think that's definitely better.
之後 我想一切一定會好轉
l mean, this is our second time around, David.
我們已是第二次設法復合
l didn't expect us to get carried away, you know.
我不冀望有多大進展
Then l guess ''congratulations'' is the right thing to say.
我想我該對你說聲恭喜
David, it's Eliijah.
我是伊萊
it Wasso obvious.
事情很明顯
it Was this one issue that brought it back forme
有本漫畫讓我想起了一切
Century Comics 117.
世紀漫畫117期
That's Where this group, the Coalition of Evil,
邪惡聯盟想察探
tried to ascertain the Weakness of every superhero,
英雄們的弱點
because they all have one, just like you.
他們跟你一樣 都有弱點
Your bones don't break. Mine do.
你的骨頭不會斷 我的會
That's clear. Your cells react to bacteria and viruses.
你我的細胞對病菌有不同反應
differently than mine.
我和你不一樣
You don't get sick. L do. That's also clear.
你不生病 我會 這也很清楚
But for some reason,
但基於某種原因
you and l react the exact same Way to Water.
你我對水的反應是一樣的
We swallow it too fast, We choke.
喝太快 我們都會嗆到
We get some in our lungs, We drown.
吸進肺裏 我們就會溺死
However unreal it may seem,
雖然很不真實
We are connected, you and l.
但我們有關連
We're on the same curve,
我們在同一條曲線上
just on opposite ends.
只是身處不同的兩端
The point of all this is We now know something We didn't.
重點是我們知道了一件事
You have a Weakness
你有弱點
Water.
水
it's like your kryptonite.
那是你的罩門
You hearing me, David?
你聽見了嗎
Audrey?
奧莉
What happened?
怎麼了
l thought l was... l thought l was dead.
我以為我死了
Me, too.
我也是
ls she all right?
她沒事吧
l think her leg's broken.
我想她的腳斷了
Are you hurt?
你有受傷嗎
Hey, man, are you hurt?
老兄 你有受傷嗎
Hello?
喂
l Wasn't injured in that car accident.
那場車禍裏我並未受傷
David.
大衛
I've never been injured, Eliijah.
我從未受過傷
What am l Supposed to do?
我該怎麼做
Go to where people are.
去人群中走走
You Won't have to look very long.
你不用太久就會找到的
lt's all right to be afraid, David,
害怕是正常的
because this part Won't be like a comic book.
因為這部份跟漫畫不一樣
Real life doesn't fit into little boxes that Were drawn for it.
現實世界與漫畫格子並不一樣
There's one in the first row. it's the second one.
第一排第二個
Yes. it's the second one over.
對 數過去第二個
Go back to Africa!
滾回非洲去吧
Hey, what's your name?
你叫什麼名字
l think you drank too much.
你喝醉了
Can l come in?
我能進去嗎
Who are you?
你是誰
l like your house.
我喜歡你家
Can l come in?
我能進去嗎
What is this?
你要幹什麼
No. You can't come in.
不 你不能進來
Are you sure?
你確定
What are you...
你幹什麼...
It's okay.
沒事了
One more.
再一下
it's okay. it's okay.
沒事了
l had a bad dream.
我做了個惡夢
it's over now.
沒事了
It's me.
是我啊
I don't know.
我不知道
l can't believe you'd think that.
你怎會那樣想
I'm just asking you.
我正要問你嘛
I'm making French toast.
我要做法國土司
I've been thinking about Eliijah Price.
我一直在想普伊萊
lf he shows up again, l think We should call the police, okay?
他要是再出現 我們就叫警察
Okay?
好嗎
Okay.
好
拯救
You were right.
你是對的
This is one of Johann Davis' earliest drawings.
這是戴維強納森最早期的作品
See the villain's eyes?
注意看那壞蛋的眼睛
They're larger than the other characters'.
比其他人物的還要大
They insinuate a slightly skewed perspective
暗示他們用一種歪曲的角度
on how they see the world
看待整個世界
Just off normal.
有點不正常
He doesn't look scary.
他看起來並不可怕
Mm hmm. That's what l said to my son,
我對我兒子也這麼說
but he says there's always 2 kinds.
他說漫畫裏只有兩種壞人
There's the soldier villain who fights the hero with his hands,
普通壞蛋用雙手打擊英雄
and then there's the real threat the
還有一種是真正的大惡人
brilliant and evil archenemy
聰明又邪惡的大魔王
who fights the hero with his mind.
用腦袋來打擊英雄
Are you Elijah's mother?
你是伊萊的母親
l am.
沒錯
I'm helping him with the sale.
我在幫他沖業績
Nice to meet you. I'm David Dunn.
幸會 我是鄧大衛
He's spoken of you.
他提過你
Says you're becoming friends.
他說你們成了朋友
We are.
是啊
Looks like he's doing good today.
看來他今天情況不錯
I'm very proud of him.
我很為他驕傲
He's come through a lot in his life
他這輩子受了很多苦
a couple of bad spells l thought had broken him.
許多時刻 我真以為他不行了
They were bad...
那些時刻真可怕
but he made it.
但他熬過來了
Yes, he did.
沒錯
He's kind of a miracle.
他真是個奇跡
Yes, he is.
沒錯
I'll tell him you're here.
我去跟他說你來了
Thank you.
謝謝
it has begun.
一切已經開始了
Tell me something, David.
告訴我
When you woke up this morning, was it still there?
你今晨起床還有那種感覺嗎
The sadness?
悲傷感
No.
沒有
l think this is where we shake hands. Did you see it?
我想我們該握個手了
l worked in that building 25 years.
我在那旅館工作25年了
l know all its secrets.
我知道它問題在哪
Secrets?
問題
Like if there ever was a fire on floors 1 , 2, or 3,
只要隨便哪一層樓著火...
everyone in that hotel would be burned alive.
旅館裏的人就都會被活活烤死
Passengers aren't allowed in there.
旅客是不准進去那裏的
墨西哥土石流
Do you know What the scariest thing is?
知道什麼事最可怕嗎
To not know your place in this world,
不知道自己歸屬於何處
to not know why you're here.
不知道自己存在的意義
That's... That's just an awful feeling.
那種感覺真糟糕
What have you done?
你做了什麼
l almost gave up hope.
我幾乎放棄了希望
There Were so many times l questioned myself.
我質疑過自己許多次
You killed all those people.
你殺了那些人
But l found you.
但我找到了你
So many sacrifices...
犧牲了這麼多人...
Just to find you.
只為了找到你
jesus Christ.
老天爺
Now that we know who you are...
現在我們知道你是誰
l know who l am.
我也知道我是誰了
I'm not a mistake.
我不是個錯誤
It all makes sense.
一切都很合理
In a comic, you know how you can tell who the arch villain's going to be?
在漫畫裏 誰會是大魔王呢
He's the exact opposite Of the hero,
就是英雄的對手
and most times, they're friends, like you and me.
跟你我一樣大多時候是朋友
l should've known way back when.
我早該明白這點的
You know why, David?
你知道為什麼嗎
Because of the kids.
因為那些小孩
鄧大衛帶領有關當局前往"限量珍藏"
查獲三起恐怖主義活動的證據
They called me Mr Glass.
他們叫我玻璃娃娃
普伊萊經裁定為精神異常
而被送入精神病院